Guide to the John Condry papers, 1967-1993.
Condry, John papers
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
John Condry papers, 1967-1993.
23-13-3741
John C. Condry
0.4 cubic foot.
Publications
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Includes publications and papers written by Condry concerning his research on the psychology of television and its impact on children.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Professor in the Dept. of Human Development (1966-1993) and Director of the Center for Research on the Effects of Television.
Condry graduated from West Virigina University with an A.B. degree in 1961 and an M.A. in 1962. He received his PhD in social psychology in 1966 from the University of California at Los Angeles. His entire teaching career was spent at Cornell with sabbaticals at the University of Kansas and at Stanford University.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Includes publications and papers written by Condry concerning his research on the psychology of television and its impact on children.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Condry, John C.; Condry, John C.; Cornell University--Faculty.; Cornell University Center for Research on the Effects of Television.
Subjects:
Television broadcasting--Psychological aspects.; Television and children--United States.; Mass media and children.; Television broadcasting--Social aspects z United States.; Television viewers.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- "Intrinsic Motivation and the Process of Learning", 1967 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- "Characteristics of Peer and Adult Oriented Children" -Journal of Marriage and the Family, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- "The Role of Incentives in Socialization" -The Hidden Costs of Rewards, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- "Can Education Be Made 'Intrinsically Interesting' to Children?" -Current Topics in Early Childhood Education, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- "Television and the Social Ecology of Childhood", 1980 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- "The Effect Pattern of Outcome and Base Rate Information on Perceptions of Success and Failure: Implications for Learned Helplessness", 1981 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- "Experimental Approaches to Intrinsic Motivation: Implications for the Use of Social Control" -American Psychological Association, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- "Television and the Future" -NYS Association for the Education of Young Children Newsletter, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- "The Effects of Pattern Outcomes and Comparative Information on Reactions to Success and Failure" -Eastern Psychological Association, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Proposal - "Motivation, Computer Technology and Education", 1982 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Apple Education Foundation, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- "Differential Response to a Film Labeled Real vs. Fictitious" -American Psychological Association, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- "Educational and Recreational Uses of Computer Technology -Youth and Society, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- "Character Portrayals and Social Values in TV Commercials" -American Psychological Convention, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- "Character Portrayals and Social Values in U.S. Network TV Commercials" -International Television Studies Conference -American Psychological Association Convention, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- "Emotional Responses to Video Material: The Role of Ego Involvement, Perceived Reality, Empathy and Sex", 1984 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- "Gender Identity and Social Competence" -Sex Roles, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Proposal - Research on an Archive of Telvision Ads, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- "Character Portrayals in Television Commercials: New Evidence Concerning Gender Differences and Social Reality", 1985 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- "The Effect of Perceived Reality on Adults' Responses to Filmed and Televised Events" - American Psychological Association, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- "The Non-Program Content of Saturday Morning Television", 1985 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- "Sex and Aggression: The Influence of Gender Labels on the Perception of Aggression in Children" - Child Development, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- "Effect of TV Commercials and Public Service Announcements on Viewers' Emotional Responses to Televised Events" -Eastern Psychological Association, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- "The Role of Familiarity in Social Perception: A Study of Responses to Hill Street Blue" -Eastern Psychological Association, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- "Television as Educator", 1986 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- "Enhancing Motivation: A Social Developmental Perspective", 1987 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- "The Structure of the Television Environment" -International Communication Association, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- "Anti-Drug and Pro-Drug Messages on Television", 1988 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- "Developmental Differences in Children's Reasoning about Santa Claus -and Other Fantasy Characters" - Society for Research in Child Development, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- "Living Color: Minority Portrayals and Cross-Racial Interactions on TV", 1988 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- "Nonprogram Content of Children's Television" -Journal of Broadcasting and Electronic Media, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 31)
- "The Psychology of Television" - Reviews, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- "Discriminating Real from Make-Believe on Television: A Developmental Study" -Society for Research on Child Development, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 33)
- "The Role of Familiarity in Social Perception: A Study of Responses to Television Drama", 1989 (Box 1, Folder 34)
- Poster and Papers Concerning Television, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 35)
- "Program and Non-Program Content of Children's Television 1970-1990" -Society for Research in Child Development, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 36)
- "Smart Army, Dumb TV", 1991 (Box 1, Folder 37)
- "Overview of Special Issue on Intrinsic Motivation" "Afterward: What's Left Out of Intrinsic Motivation Theory?", 1992 (Box 1, Folder 38)
- "Children's Television Before and After the Children's Television Act of 1990" - Poster, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 39)
- "The Development of the Collectivist and the Individualist Self-Concept" and its Effect on the Response to Television Commercials" - Proposal, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 40)
- "Thief of Time, Unfaithful Servant: Television and the American Child" -Daedalus, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 41)
- "Patterns of Task Outcomes as a Factor in the Perception of Control" (Box 1, Folder 42)
- "Perceived Control as a Function of Coherent Versus Random Patterns of Outcomes" (Box 1, Folder 43)
- Prospectus for Book, 1982 - 1988 (Box 1, Folder 44)
- Research Grants, 1982 - 1984 (Box 1, Folder 45)
- Reviews by Condry, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 46)
- Proposal - Computer Aided Instruction, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 47)
- Federal Trade Commission - Hearings, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 48)
- Federal Trade Commission - Comments Before Them, 1991 - 1993 (Box 1, Folder 49)
- Graduate Student Project with Robert Rieger, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 50)